JOHANNES KRUSE

Address: Göteborg Plads 15, 2150, Copenhagen, Denmark

Contacts: +45 93 95 95 56 | Johannes-Kruse@hotmail.com | https://linkedin.com/in/JohannesKruse

DOB: $\sqrt{9}/\sqrt{25}/\sqrt{9025}$

GitHub: https://github.com/JohannesKruse

Summary: I specialize in machine learning, natural language processing, and recommender systems. Throughout my coursework, volunteer involvement, and previous work I have become exceptionally structured, proactive, and solution orientated. I am a disciplined learner (Kaggle and Python enthusiast) who thrives being challenged and explore opportunities to continuously expand my competences.



EDUCATION

12/2021	Present Technical University of Denmark & Ekstra Bladet	dustrial Ph.D. Student	Kgs. Lyngby & Copenhagen, DK
	Project title: Responsible Recommender Systems for Danis	sh News Publishing (RRS-DK)	
	Courses: Deep Learning, Reinforcement Learning, Machin Entrepreneurship in Technical Science	ne Learning Summer School, Advanced Topics in I	Machine Learning,
	Developed and implemented the core recommendation sy significant traffic growth for the site	ystem for EkstraBladet.dk, improving user engage	ement and driving
09/2018	- 04/2021 Technical University of Denmark M	Sc Mathematical Modelling & Computation	Kgs. Lyngby, DK
	Courses: Machine Learning, Advanced Modelling, Till Optimisation, Computational Data Analysis	me Series Analysis, Computational Data Anal	ysis, Constrained
	Involved in the Danish research project WriteReader by everesidual Networks and Convolutional Neural Networks	aluating machine generated captions with Deep Le	arning using Deep
	Thesis: Deep learning for Natural Language Processing. Ex of enriching word embeddings. Grade: 12	xploring the use of Knowledge Graph technologies	with the objective
		xchange Student	Barcelona, ES
	Courses: Deep Learning, Kernel-based Machine Learning a Warehousing	and Multivariate Modelling, Human Language Eng	ineering, and Data
09/2015		Sc Biomedical Engineering	Kgs. Lyngby, DK
	Courses: Advanced Engineering Mathematics, Physics, Clinicians, Cell and Tissue Biology, Medical Imaging		
	Thesis: Computational Neuroimaging. Investigation of tra applying data analysis using Python programming. Grade:		ned brain states by
		xchange Student	New York, US
	Courses: Biomechanics, Biomedical Product Development	t, Skilled Performance & Training	
	Gained a valuable insight in the process and procedures of	of budgeting, fundraising, and meeting deadlines,	as well as quickly
	learning how to adjust to new environments, cultures, and	teaching styles	
	CATION		
	Johannes Kruse, Kasper Lindskow, Michael Riis Andersen experience on ekstrabladet.dk with recommender systems. Systems (RecSys '23). Association for Computing Machine https://doi.org/10.1145/3604915.3610248	In Proceedings of the 17th ACM Conference on R	
	Sanne Vrijenhoek, Lien Michiels, Johannes Kruse, Alain S <i>The First Workshop on Normative Design and Evaluation</i> Conference on Recommender Systems (RecSys '23). Assochttps://doi.org/10.1145/3604915.3608757	of Recommender Systems. In Proceedings of the 1"	7th ACM
	Johannes Kruse and Lars Kai Hansen. 2019. <i>Det Etiske Rå</i>	d – Redegørelse om sundhedswearables og big da	ta. pp. 116–141.
STUDE	ENTS		
	Zhijian Feng, 2023, Technical University of Denmark & E MSc thesis: <i>Using Image Information in Deep Learning-Base Control</i>		
	Magnus Waldemar Hoff Harder & Nikolaj Bach Meineche		a Bladet

BSc thesis: Transformer-based News Recommendations: Leveraging User Click-History with Deep Learning

WORK EXPERIENCE

WUKN	LATERIT	LICE				
04/2021	-12/2021	Ekstra Bladet	Machine Learning Engineer	Copenhagen, DK		
			ing recommender systems focusing on personali	zed news recommendation		
		ies of modelling and ranking of news ar				
			olders to ensure an understanding of the comple	ex mathematical algorithm		
	- 1	mented in production and an agreement	1 0 0 1 0			
			lopment for model training and evaluation, and	employing state-of-the-art		
		ation systems for productions use at eks				
07/2020	-09/2020	Infosys Limited	InStep Intern	Bangalore, IND		
			component to existing enterprise search engine			
			or Question Answering and Question Generation	modules utilizing state-of-		
		ine learning algorithms				
01/2020		Implement Consultant Group	Junior Consultant	Copenhagen, DK		
			ious companies to become more data-driven by o			
			atilizing machine learning algorithms to extract	and visualize topics within		
		and reduce the number of organizationa				
09/2018	3 - 09/2019	AudienceProject	Data Analyst	Copenhagen, DK		
			ntences recognition enabling categorizing a docu	ument of more than 3.500		
		less than two seconds				
	_		team that collaborates with two of the major dep			
03/2018	3 - 09/2018	The Danish Ethics Committee	External Consultant	Copenhagen, DK		
			gn' which examines the possibilities of enabling a	i citizen to secure complete		
	control of their personal data stored in public spaces via technical means					
			entists in the field of cryptography and academica	ılly communicated relevant		
		in a comprehensive format for the mem				
	6 - 06/2018		Teaching Assistant	Kgs. Lyngby, DK		
			s of the syllabus. Courses: Calculus and Algebra	l and 2		
	-	fessors in evaluating and grading mathe	•			
02/2016	6 - 05/2018	Novozymes	Student Assistant	Bagsvaerd, DK		
			hile identifying and implementing new ideas for	optimization of calibration		
	routines and procedures					
			e full-size washing machine program in the Ho	busehold Care division by		
00/201-		ng and streamlining the calibration routi				
		Rensselaer Polytechnic Institute	Research Assistant	New York, US		
			cience Department, following rigorous scientific	protocols and instructing		
	subjects in the	he processes of the experiments				
	MARKE					
	NTEER					
_	3 - 08/2018	Engineering World Health	Expatriate Volunteer	Dolakha District, NP		
			Himalayas, Nepal, for a duration of six weeks			
☐ Cooperated with the Ministry of Health of Nepal and the local hospital to contribute to FN's 2030 development goals of ensuring						
	universal he	alth benefits to all people around the wo	orld			
OTHE	n					
OTHE:		Data Change Comment				
IT Skil		Python, Git, R, Microsoft Office, SQI				
Languages		Danish (Native) – English (Fluent) – Spanish (Intermediate)				
		Culture (Lived abroad in Greenland, Canada, United States), Climbing (certified rock-climbing instructor), Freediving (Completed an open-sea dive to 28 meters), Hiking (Almost hugged a wild bear)				
				bear)		
Person	al Skills	Leadership – Teamwork – Structured	 Innovative – Initiative – Rational 			